Register to The Charles Ives Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Correspondence, Series III; 13 boxes
  - Correspondence - General, III.A
    - Harrison, Lou (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Charles Ives, [1943 Sep ?], [1944 Oct ?]; 2 drafts (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Harrison, 1944 Oct 23; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Charles Ives to above, draft (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Harrison, 1944 Dec; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - 1945 Jul 22, typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - reply to above, draft (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, 1946 Feb; draft (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Harrison, 1946 Feb 19; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, 1946 Feb 19; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Charles Ives for 1946 Feb 19, draft (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Harrison, 1946 Feb; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Charles Ives for 1946 Mar 6, draft (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, 1946 Mar 6; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Harrison, 1946 Apr 1[?]; autograph LS (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, 1946 Apr 8; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Harrison, 1946 Apr [?]; typed letter (copy) (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Harrison, 1946 Apr 14; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, 1946 Apr 21; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Harrison, 1946 May; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Charles Ives for 1946 Jun 16, no date; draft (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, 1946 Jun 16; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Charles Ives for 1946 Jun 28, draft (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, 1946 Jun 28; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Harrison, 1946 Jul 24; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Charles Ives for 1946 Aug 9, no date; draft (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - (not sent), no date; draft (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, 1946 Aug 9; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Harrison, [1946 Jul 24?]; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Charles Ives for 1946 Nov 20, no date; draft (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, 1946 Nov 20; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Charles Ives, 1946 Dec [?]; draft (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Harrison, 1947 Jan [?]; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, 1947 Jan 15; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Charles Ives for 1947 Jan 17, no date; draft (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, 1947 Jan 17; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, 1947 Feb 14; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Cage to Charles Ives, 1947 May 13; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - 1947 May [?], autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Charles Ives, 1947 [spring?]; draft (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Cage, 1947 Jun 9; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Harrison, 1947 Jul 2 [?], 1947 Jul 9; 2 typed letters signed (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Charles Ives answer to above, no date; 2 drafts (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - to ?, [?1947 Jul]; draft (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Charles Ives, [?1947 Jul); draft (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Charles Ives, [?1947 Nov]; draft (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Harrison, 1948 Dec; autograph letter signed card (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Harrison, 1949 Feb 1; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, 1949 Feb 10, 1951 Feb 15; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Harrison, 1952 Jul 19; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, [1952] Jul 24; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Harrison, [1952] [?] no date; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Charles Ives to Harrison, no date; draft (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - note from John Kirkpatrick re leaves for 114 Songs (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Herrmann, Bernard (Box 30, Folder 4)
      The correspondence of Charles Ives to Herrmann is in the collection of Herrmann papers with his widow, Norma Shepard Herrmann, in London. Photocopies were made in 1979 by William Brooks. These are as follows: Nineteen letters, one original only in photocopy; one in Harmony Ives's hand signed "Charles;" one signed "Charles and Harmony Ives" in Harmony's hand; thirteen written and signed by Harmony; two written by Edith Ives and signed "Edith Ives for Charles Ives;" two written and signed by Edith. The dates cover two periods: 1936 Jul 18 to 1938 Oct (twelve letters); and 1945 Apr 22 to 1946 Sep 19 (six letters). One letter, from Edith, sent from Taormina, Italy is undated. This was probably written early 1933. These copies have been placed in the front of folder 30/4 preceding Herrmann's correspondence to Ives.
      III.A/29/8/Fletcher
      X.D/65/3; X.D/67/17/Library Correspondence and Gifts after 1955
      - Charles Ives to Herrmann - verso to Moross transcribed by John Kirkpatrick, 1932 [mid] Dec; draft (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Charles Ives, [?1936 Jun]; draft (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Herrmann, 1936 Jul 14; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Charles Ives to above, no date; draft 1 (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - no date, draft (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Herrmann with 2 mm of music, 1936 Sep 14; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Charles Ives to above, no date; draft (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Charles Ives, no date; draft (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Herrmann, 1936 Oct 2; *typed letter (copy) (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Charles Ives, [1936 Oct 17] no date; draft (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Herrmann, 1936 Nov 5; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - response to above, no date; draft (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Herrmann, 1937 Aug 6; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Charles Ives, [?1937 Sep); draft (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Herrmann, 1937 Oct 26; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Charles Ives to above, draft (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Herrmann, 1937 Nov 1; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Charles Ives, [ca. 1938 Oct]; draft (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Herrmann, program (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Charles Ives, 1946 Jun 3 [?]; draft (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Herrmann, Lucille Fletcher, 1941 Sep 27, Oct; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Herrmann (enc list radio program), 1943 Mar 8; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Charles Ives answer to 1943 Mar 8, 1943 [?] no date; 2 drafts (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Herrmann (enc typed letter Munker, Ernest, 1943 Mar 22), 1943 Apr 28; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives, no date; draft 1 (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives, no date; draft 2 (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - 1945 Jun 23, typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - no date, 2 drafts (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Herrmann, 1946 May 29; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Herrmann, Bernard, draft (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Herrmann, 1946 Sep 15; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives for 1946 Sep 19, draft (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, 1946 Sep 19; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives, draft (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Herrmann, 1950 May 22; *typed (copy) (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Herrmann, 1950 Jun 12; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Herrmann, 1950 Aug 20; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives to above, draft (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives, no date; draft (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives, no date; draft (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - to Herrmann, Wendy, no date; memo draft (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives, no date; 2 drafts (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Hess, Maud M., 1947 Feb 28; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - [Hess], Inez, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Hewitt, Caroline, 1922 Dec 28; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - Hewitt, 1935 Jun 21; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Heyman, Katherine corrected typescript for radio program, 1928 Mar 5 (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - with autograph note (from scrapbook), calling card (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Heyman, 1926 Sep 16 to 1927 Aug 8; 7 autograph letters signed (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Charles Ives, 1927 Sep 9; typed letter signed (copy) (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Heyman, 1927 Oct 6; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - intro John Kirkpatrick, no date; card (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Heyman, 1928 Mar 23; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - with program, 1930 Jan 24; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Heyman, 1930 Dec 14, 1931 May 9, Sep 11, 1934 Jul 16; 4 autograph letters signed (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - [1937 ? 26], program (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Charles Ives, [1942 Apr 15); autograph card (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - no date, autograph letter signed memo (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Highet, Gilbert
      See 30/18/Myrick
    - Hijman
      See 27/9/Brickhause, E.L.
    - Hill, Lee, [?] Sep 19 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Hill, Edward Burlingame
      See III.B/34/9/Hopkins
    - Hill, M.W., [?] Aug 15; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Hill, Susan Benedict, 1896 Aug 20; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - by Harmony Twichell Ives of Hirschman, S.A., [1940 ? ?]; autograph letter signed (copy) (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Hochberg, Morris, 1947 Nov 8; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Hoffmann, George, 1926 Jul 16; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Hofmann, W., 1932 Dec 20; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Hofmann, no date; autograph letter signed Christmas (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Holbrooke, Josef, 1921 Mar 23; autograph card
      - Holbrooke, [?] Mar 16; program (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - 1921 Mar 23, 2 advertisements (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Holbrooke, 1921 Mar, 1922 Aug, [1922 Aug]; 3 programs (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Holbrooke, autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Holbrooke, clipping (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Holden, R.
      29/1/Donovan
      36/7/Yale
    - Hollas, Mr. and Mrs., 1930 Jul 26; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Charles Ives - Hollister, no date; 3 drafts (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Holman-Black, Charles, 1923 May 25; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Holmes, Lawrence, (1934 Oct 16]; program announcement
      - [John Kirkpatrick] to Ibbs and Tillett re Holmes, 1964 Sep 27; typed letter (copy) (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Ibbs and Tillett (Walker, D.G.) to John Kirkpatrick, 1964 Oct 7; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Falkner, Keith to John Kirkpatrick, 1964 Oct 14; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - [John Kirkpatrick] to Holmes, Lawrence, 1964 Oct 19; typed letter (copy) (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - [John Kirkpatrick] to Holmes, 1965 Jun 19; autograph (copy) (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - John Kirkpatrick to Holmes and envelope (returned) 1968 Aug 7, autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - John Kirkpatrick to Major Walker (Ibbs and Tillett), typed letter (copy) (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Walker, D.G. to John Kirkpatrick, 1968 Aug 30; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Holmes, Lawrence, autograph Christmas card with note (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Holter, Sarah, 1920 Sep 30, [1922 ? Sep 6]; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Hopekirk, Helen, 1935 Jun 11; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Howard, Mary Shipman, 1941 Jul 14; autograph card signed
      - Howard, [?] Apr 1928; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Charles Ives to Howard, John Tasker for 1938 Feb 3, draft 1 (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - for 1938 Feb 3, draft 2 (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Charles Ives to Howard, [1930 Jun 30]; draft (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - (not sent), [1928 Jun 30]; drafts for encs (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - sent, 1930 Jun 30; copies of encs (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Huebert, Diana, 1935 Nov 26; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - (Becker attached), typed letter (memo) (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Hull, Anne
    - Hull, Roger
      See III.B/34/16/MONY
    - Humphrey, Muriel M., 1923 May 4; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Hunt, Harold J., 1932 Nov 6; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Huntington, Anna Hyatt
      See X.D/67/25/Library Correspondence
    - Charles Ives to Hu... [?], draft (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Hyatt, Agnes, 1947 Oct 18; typed letter (copy) (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Illoway, Doris G., 1951 Apr 9, Apr 19; 2 typed letters signed (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Ives (Box 30, Folder 9)
      See also the John Kirkpatrick Papers.
      The correspondence of Charles Ives to family members dating from 1880 were found by John Kirkpatrick in papers given him by Ives's cousin Amelia Van Wyck. They were added to these papers in 1979. (See 33/1-2).
      For Harmony Ives with Yale Library see: III.B/36/8/Yale Music Library, X.D/67/17/Library Correspondence.
    - Ives, Amelia (Mrs. Brewster), [1933?]; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Ives, Bigelow, 1950 Nov 29; autograph letter signed
      - Silver-Burdett Co. to Bigelow Ives, 1950 Nov 27; enc (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Ives, Bigelow (enc 4 news articles), [?] Mar 10; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Ives, Brewster, [?] Oct 31; autograph letter signed
      - Harmony Twichell Ives to Ives, Brewster, 1947 Sep 15; autograph letter signed (copy) (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Charles Ives to Ives, Brewster, no date; autograph letter signed (copy) (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Ives, Charles to family
      See 33/1-2
    - Ives, Chester, 1933 Apr 4, Oct 8, 1933 Aug 23; 3 autograph letters signed
      - Charles Ives to Ives, Chester, 1934 Aug 19; autograph postcard signed (copy) (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Ives, Chester, 1934 Sep 5, Sep 6, [?] Mar 29; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Ives, Chester to Charles Ives, 1940 Feb 8; check (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - 1941 Apr 25, expense list (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - 1941 Jun 5, receipt of loan (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Ives, Chester, 1941 Jun 10; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Charles Ives to Ives, Chester, no date; autograph letter signed (copy) (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Charles Ives to Ives, Chester, no date; verso check, memo (copy) (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Charles Ives, no date; autograph postcard signed (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Ives, Chester to Harmony Twichell Ives, [?] Apr 15; typed letter signed (copy) (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Ives, Edith to Charles Ives, 1928 Mar 22; autograph card signed
      - Ives, Edith to MacKenzie, Findlay 1928 Jun 18, 1929 Jun 18 (given by MacKenzie to Vivian Perlis in 1973), 1930 Jul 27, 3 typed letters (copy) (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - MacKenzie to Edith Ives, 1929 Aug 7; autograph card signed (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Ives, Edith to "Mother & Daddy", 1929 Aug 21, no date; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Ives, Harmony
      See 32/10/Twichell
    - Ives, Mrs. Howard M. (Annie), 1933 Oct 29; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Ives, Moss, [1905?]; autograph list
      - Ives, Moss, 1919 Aug 18, 1933 May 25, 1934 Sep 11, Oct 25; 4 typed letters signed (Box 30, Folder 9)
        See also III.A/28/3/Cowell 1932 May 7
      - Ives, Moss to Burt [Twichell], 1931 Jun 17; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Ives, Moss (by Keane, Cecelia, F.), 1937 Feb 5; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Ives, Moss, no date; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Ives, Moss to Harmony Twichell Ives, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Ives, Moss to Harmony Twichell Ives, no date; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Keeler, Gerard S. to Ives, Moss, 1924 Apr 28; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Twichell, Burton P. to Ives, Moss, [?] Jun 10; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Ives, Moss [Abide with Me], autograph music (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Ives, Mrs. Moss
      See 30/14/Kirkpatrick 1957 Nov 3
    - Ives, Richard, 1925 Jun 4; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Ives, Sarane, [?] no date; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - excerpt, 1951 Jul 29; *typed (copy) (Box 30, Folder 9)
        See also 30/14/Kirkpatrick (2)
    - Ives, Sarah, 1937 Oct 15; typed (copy) (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Jacobi, Frederick, 1940 Jan ?; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - Charles Ives to above, 1940 Jan 2 [?]; draft 1 (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - Charles Ives to above, 1940 Jan [?]; draft 2? (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - Charles Ives to above, 1940 Jan [?]; draft 3? (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Jacobi, Irene, 1940 Jan 19; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - Jacobi, Irene, 1940 Feb 8; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Jagow, Charles, no date; autograph letter (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Jaksic, 1951 Sep 8; *typed letter (copy) (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Janovisek, [?] Mrs. E., 1951 Mar 6; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Janssen, Werner, 1935 Dec 2; telegram (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Johnson, Alvin, 1934 Apr 3; 2 typed letters signed (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Johnson, Frances H., 1939 Dec 5; envelope (Box 30, Folder 10)
      enc folder with Charles Ives marginalia
    - Johnson, Reber, 1941 Apr 3; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Johnston, Richard, 1946 May 19; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Jones, Richard, 1952 Jun 26, Sep 9; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Joseph, Shirley, 1922 Aug 8; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Joslin, Elliott to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1936 Jan 21; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - response Charles Ives to above, no date; draft (Box 30, Folder 10)
        see also III.B/34/14/Joslin Clinic
    - Judson, Arthur
      See III.B/35/4/New York Philharmonic
    - to Jurasky, A., no date; draft (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Kahn, [?]
      See folder 30/12
    - Kalmus, Edwin
      See III.B/34/6/Cos Cob Press
    - Kastner, Harold
    - Kauffman, Charles (Box 30, Folder 11)
      Photocopies of correspondence from Charles Ives to Kauffman given to Vivian Perlis 1970.
      - Charles Ives to Kauffman, 1932 Jan 3; autograph letter signed (copy) (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, 1942 Jan 26; autograph letter signed (copy) (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - printed by Kauffman, "Universal Law and Democratic Principle", 1943; brochure (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - Charles Ives, [?1943]; autograph letter signed (copy) (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, 1965 Sep 25; autograph letter signed (copy) (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, [1967] Oct 7; autograph letter signed (copy) (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - Kauffman, 1969 Feb [?]; typescript of review (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - "Charles Ives, The Man", no date; typescript of article (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - (Kauffman) "The Forgotten Man", no date; poem (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - Kauffman, Charles, 2 typed poems (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Kahn, [Otto], 1921 Mar 2; typed letter (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Kastner, Harold, 1948 Sep 16, 1949 Mar 20; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Kaufman, Louis, 1940 Nov 27; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Kaye, Bess
    - Keeler, Gerrard
      See 30/9/Ives, Moss 1924 Apr 28
    - Kelly, June, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Kerr, Harrison to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1948 Oct 13, 1951 Feb 9; 2 typed letters signed (Box 30, Folder 12)
      III.B/34/4/Arrow Press and American Music Center
    - Kilborne, Helen, no date; autograph card signed (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - Kilborne, no date; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Kilborne, Mary A., no date, 1951 Mar 4; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - for Kipling, R. by Ponton, D., 1922 Aug 17; typed card (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Kirkpatrick, John
      See folders 30/13 and 30/14
    - Kleiber, Erich, 1931 Nov 25; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Klein, Sigmund, 1926 Jul 2; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - Charles Ives to Klein, 1928 Aug 30; typed (copy) (Box 30, Folder 12)
        See also III.A/31/14/Schmitz
    - Koons, Walter E., 1933 Jan 1; typed letter signed
      - Charles Ives to Koons, no date; draft (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - Koons, 1933 Mar 5, Apr 7; 2 typed letters signed (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Kroeger, Karl
    - Krenek, Ernst to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1948 Apr 5; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - Charles Ives to Krenek, Ernst, no date; draft (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Kriens, Christaan, 1922 Dec 18; typed letter signed
      - Charles Ives memos (autograph), verso (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - Kriens, 1923 Mar 16; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - Charles Ives to Kriens, Christaan, 1923 Mar 19; typed (copy) (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - Kriens, 1928 ?; autograph postcard (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Krohn, 1921 Oct 15; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - Charles Ives to above, 1921 Oct 20; typed (copy) (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Charles Ives to Kroll, Louis, no date; draft (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Charles Ives to Koussevitzky, [Serge], no date; draft (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Kirkpatrick, John (Box 30, Folder 13)
      This register lists the correspondence from John Kirkpatrick to Charles Ives. Ives's letters to Kirkpatrick have been microfilmed; they can be found on the addenda microfilm reel. The originals now belong to the John Kirkpatrick Papers at Yale. Kirkpatrick's correspondence with others relating to Ives and his music can also be found in the John Kirkpatrick Papers.
      III.A/27/7/Bell
      III.A/27/8/Bellamann
      III.A/29/3/Engel
      III.A/30/7/Heyman
      III.A/30/8/Holmes
      III.A/32/8/Szigeti
      III.B/36/8/Yale
      X.D/67/17/Gifts after 1965
      X.D/67/26/Library Correspondence
      - John Kirkpatrick, 1927 Oct 7; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - Charles Ives, 1927 Oct 10; typed letter (copy) (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - John Kirkpatrick, 1927 Oct 16; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - Charles Ives, 1928 Feb 6; typed letter (copy) (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - John Kirkpatrick, 1933 Dec 11; typed letter signed (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - John Kirkpatrick, 1934 Jan 5, Jan 18, 1934 Jul [12], 1935 Jul [24]; 4 typed letters signed (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - John Kirkpatrick with Charles Ives additions, 1935 Sep 28; typed letter signed and envelope (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - Charles Ives, no date; 3 drafts (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - Kirkpatrick, John, envelope in which John Kirkpatrick found sketches for [1935 Oct 11] (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - sketches transcribed by John Kirkpatrick, drafts (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - John Kirkpatrick, 1935 Oct 25, Nov 5, 1935 Nov 20; 3 typed letters signed (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - Charles Ives for [1935 Dec 30] drafts transcribed by John Kirkpatrick, 3 drafts (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - John Kirkpatrick, [1936 Jan]; autograph letter styped letter signeded (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - Charles Ives for [?1936 Jan 24], draft (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - John Kirkpatrick, [1936 Jan 24]; autograph letter signed (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - John Kirkpatrick "American Piano Music", 1936 Jan 28; program (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - John Kirkpatrick, [1936 Jan 29], 1936 Feb 1, 1936 [Feb 5], 1936 [May? 23]; 4 autograph letters signed (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - music example, enc (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - John Kirkpatrick, 1936 Jul 22, [1936 ?Aug 10], [1936 Aug 14], 1936 Nov 2; 4 autograph letters signed (Box 30, Folder 13)